How about variability?
那差异性呢？
First, we said, here's how to compute the variability analytically.
一开始我们说了如何分析计算差异性
But then, we said, sometimes it's maybe better to estimate it empirically.
然后我们也说有时候实证估计更好
Which should I be doing?
我该怎么做呢？
>> Well, it's usually good to start out with some kind of analytical
一般情况下 一开始先对差异性做一些分析
characterization of your variability.
是比较好的
Sometimes, that's even sufficient.
有时候甚至这样就足够了
But, if nothing else, it means that you have to look at the distribution, and
但这样就意味着你需要查看分布
start to get a feel for your data.
对数据有个大概的感觉
Which is really important as part of this process.
这对这个过程来说是非常重要的
In some cases, like where you're using counts, or probabilities,
有些情况下 比如你使用计数、概率
or averages, your data is fairly nice, it may be sufficient.
或平均值 数据如果相当好 就已经足够了
Or, it may give you a good sense of how to size your experiment.
或者能够帮助你确认实验的规模
So, at least, you can tell if you're in the ballpark.
至少你可以知道你是否是大致正确的
>> I agree. I mean,
我同意
you should always start with at least a basic analytical
你一开始应该至少对差异性进行
estimate of your variability.
基础的分析估计
Now, where we sort of encounter the problem is that with a metric like
现在 如果我们使用每次查询的收益这种指标
revenue per query,
我们会遇见的问题是
it's actually very difficult to compute the variability of that analytically.
很难分析计算差异性
It turns out that for some metrics,
而有些指标
it was actually easier to compute it empirically as opposed to analytically.
比起分析 更容易通过实证来计算
And, once we're just computing that empirically, then we were like, well,
一旦我们通过实证计算这些指标后
we may as well try it for all the other metrics.
我们也可能觉得可以对其他指标试试
Which is when we discovered some of the discrepancies between the analytical and
那我们可能会发现分析和实证计算之间的
the empirical calculation, even for something like a probability.
差异 比如对概率这些指标
We'll be discussing the reason for that more in lesson 4
我们会在第 4 课中讨论这个原因
>> Okay, and just overall,
对的 那整体来说
what are some of the main lessons you've learned about metrics?
你们在指标方面有些什么主要的经验教训？
>> You know, the one that I keep going back to over and
我不断不断重复的是
over again is the necessity of invariance, or sanity checking, right?
不变性的必要性或完整性检查
I went back to the very first experiment that Google ran,
我想到 Google 运行的第一个实验
which is back in the year 2000, where we tested out should we showing 10 results,
在 2000 年 我们进行测试 我们应该得出
20 results, or 30 results.
10 个、20 个或 30 个结果
It seemed a very straightforward experiment,
这看上去是非常直接的实验
but the results were actually really weird.
但结果看着非常奇怪
And, what we actually found was that it was because the latency was changing as
最后我们发现 这是因为在我们运行实验的过程中
we ran those experiments.
延迟时间更改了
That was actually causing the change in the user response,
这造成了用户响应方面的变更
as opposed to the number of resolves.
而不是解析的数量
And so, in that situation, using the latency as an invariant,
所以在这种情况下 将延迟时间看作不变量
as opposed to evaluation metric,was the right answer.
而不是评估指标 是正确的答案
>> Now, there's another story where, for a variety of reasons,
另外 由于某些原因
we accidentally put an IFrame, an invisible IFrame, over the ads.
我们意外地在广告上放了一个看不见的 IFrame
And so, at least in some browsers, you actually couldn't click on the ad.
所以 至少在一些浏览器中 你无法点击广告
Being able to know and say, oh, well when click-through rate changes by,
所以 要知道如果点击率发生那么大的变更
that large an amount, that's just simply not possible.
是不太可能的
That is also, like, a really big thing to understand, and know,
这也让你更加明白了
and have intuition about your system.
要对系统有自己的直觉
>> You also have to just sort of see how these things behave in practice.
你还要看看这些事情在实践中是怎样的
When we first started looking at what made a bad query, a query where
我们一开始在考虑怎样的查询算是不好的查询
a user didn't find the results they were hoping for in their search.
用户在搜索中没有找到他们想要的结果
The thing that everybody said is, well,
大家都在说
a bad query is the query where people click on a bunch of results, like two or
坏的查询就是点开多个结果
more results, or they hit the next page button.
比如两个或更多的结果 或者点击下一页的按钮
Because, they obviously haven't found what they wanted on the first page.
因为他们明显没有在第一页上找到他们想要的东西
Now, it turned out very quickly that, that wasn't a great way to pick out bad
但很快就发现这并不是指出坏查询的好方法
queries, because you've heard the song from Avenue Q, The Internet is for Porn?
你可能听过 Avenue Q 的一首歌 The Internet is for Porn (互联网是色情的世界)
Well, we get a lot of porn queries, and
我们收到很多色情片的查询
for various reasons, we won't talk about here.
基于各种原因 我们不会在这里讨论这个话题
It appears that they all basically look like that.
看上去它们都像是我们之前谈及的那种情况
And so, we were really just picking out a lot of sort of browsing porn
所以 在这个过程中
queries in the process.
我们也把很多色情片的查询选成坏的查询
The second thing that came up here, which is more sort of time critical,
而第二点与时间更为相关
is when we first started using these metrics,
当我们第一次使用这些指标时
people were really using search engines for navigational results.
大家可能只是使用搜索引擎寻找导航结果
They were looking for a particular store,
比如搜索特定的商店
looking for a particular home page.
特定的主页
And so, you really got this behavior where people did a query, and
所以就这样的行为来看 大家查询的时候
then they clicked on the first result, and they were happy.
点击第一个结果 就会很开心
They found what they wanted.
找到他们自己想要的东西了
But today, the amount of content on the internet is more diverse,
但是 到了现在 网络上的内容非常多元化了
plus people have gotten used to search engines being smart, so
加上人们已经很习惯智能的搜索引擎了
they really do more complicated tasks.
所以他们开始想完成一些复杂的任务
And, even if you're looking for a person,
你想要找一个人
you might end up clicking on their Twitter feed,
你最后可能会点击进入他们的 Twitter 账户
you click on their Facebook page, you click on their university home page.
他们的 Facebook 页面 或者他们的大学主页
So, the behavior has really shifted.
这个行为就变化了
And, this is a good example of a metric that seemed like a good idea,
这个例子就说明 有些之前看上去很好的指标
worked at a particular point in time, or didn't work, and then, sort of,
在某个时间段很有用或者没有用
stopped working as the use case evolved for the website.
但是在网站的使用案例改进之后就不再有用了